I'm a reindeer!
It just talks!
Pirate this, pirate that, who cares?
I hate pirates!
Every stinking last one of them!
So why would I be on this ship?
The only things I love are money and tangerines,
and I don't see either around here.
It's a little early for this much of a racket.
I was trying to sleep.
There's gotta be some way off this ship.
I don't know what's going on here,
but I don't see any point in sticking around.
A mysterious boy with a horn and Robin's deduction!
Our navigator.
I guess I can postpone that heart attack.
Not that I'm sad to see that guy go,
but we're losing people left and right.
Our navigator's likely headed for the island.
I doubt she'll go too far.
She won't do anything drastic.
Not until she thinks things through anyway.
Let's hope so.
I'm starving to death here!
You look delicious!
Jeez.
You've really got a one-track mind, don't you?
Mm.
Oh well.
I guess we can try to figure out
just what the hell is going on here while we're eating.
But first things first,
I'm afraid I never caught your name, miss.
It's Nico Robin.
Despite the circumstances, it's a pleasure.
Can you fill us in on our history?
Sure.
There's no way in hell.
I wouldn't be caught dead on that ship.
The only thing pirates are good for
is destroying other people's lives.
I've got to figure out some way
to get back to Kokoyashi Village.
Come on ashore, lady.
I'm glad that you've wandered my way.
Very glad indeed.
We have to find theükle,
but you have to go.
There's no way in hell.
I wouldn't be caught dead on that ship.
The only thing pirates are good for
is destroying other people's lives.
I've got to figure out some way
to get back to Kokoyashi Village.
Uh-uh...
Come on ashore, lady.
I'm glad that you've wandered my way.
Very glad indeed.
I haven't seen a single person.
It's a little creepy.
Maybe I'll find someone a little further up the hill.
A news booth?
What the?
What do you people want?
It's fine, dammit!
Shut up! It's the only thing I can rely on!
Well, too bad for you, then!
Let go, jerk!
I need it more than you do!
Shut up! It's mine!
I had it first! Now drop it!
Do I look like I care?
Who do you think you are?
If I knew that, there wouldn't be a problem!
What is wrong with these people?
What was that about?
Hey.
You look perplexed.
What's the matter?
Hmm.
So that's it? You need a boat?
Yeah.
The boats docked behind us are the only ones on the island.
What? Are you sure?
They all look pretty run-down like no one's used them in forever.
I guess everyone around here is too busy with other things to bother with them.
You can go ahead and check the rest of the island if you don't believe me.
It's a small island. It won't take you long at all.
You ought to stick around for a while. Might as well take it easy and enjoy yourself.
Well, I'd like to, but I really need to get going.
Oh. That's too bad.
I'm sorry.
It's okay. Don't worry about it.
Ugh.
Well, I'm feeling kind of worn out. I'd better head on home.
Hang on!
Bye! See ya!
I can't believe I'm stuck on a boat with real pirates.
So clouds are really as fluffy as they look?
Ducks and dog, horsey bird. Darn it. I want to remember all this stuff.
A Davyback fight in a marine fortress, sky islands and sand countries.
Talk about a fantastic adventure. And this is true?
Yes. All true.
Huh.
I'm sitting next to a pirate with a hundred million berry bounty on his head.
Hey, don't you got any more stories about our neat adventures?
I didn't join your crew until after you left Alabasta. Sorry. I couldn't tell you what happened before that.
Oh, man. That sucks.
I can't really say I'd buy every aspect of her story, but she's got one piece of evidence on her side.
This is exactly how I would have set this kitchen up.
So, Robin, can you tell us about yesterday before any of this happened?
Sure. But let's include the ship's doctor.
Huh?
You're still doing it backwards.
Shut up. I'll do it how I want.
You've got to be hungry. Why don't you sit down and eat?
Oh, come on. Do I look stupid to you? You really think I'm going to fall for something like that?
This conversation is nothing without your voice. Please join us. We need your brilliant input.
You dummy. You're not going to win me over by flattering me, okay?
You sure about that?
Yes. We followed the coordinates to this area of the sea.
Nami, are you sure we haven't peered off course?
Calm down. The log pose is never wrong.
Hey, Usopp, what's the lookout like up there?
Ah, give me a second.
Island ahead!
It looks like it's completely surrounded by coral reefs.
It's dangerous to push ahead in this light.
Why don't we drop anchor off the coast tonight and go ashore in the morning?
Ah!
Don't want to listen to your navigator, huh?
Hey, Sanji, no dinner for Luffy.
What?
Whatever you say, Nami!
I'm sorry!
And after that, everybody went to bed.
Well, I stayed up doing research and the swordsman was on watch.
I know it's not much, but that's it.
Everything's the same as you remember it after that.
Probably.
The pirate hunter was pissed we woke him up, so he must have fallen asleep at some point.
It would seem so.
More coffee?
Yes, please.
So the big question we need to answer is why you're the only one who didn't lose your memory.
The only difference that I can think of is that I'm the only one who stayed awake, if the swordsman did in fact fall asleep, that is.
Ah, well, I fell asleep, but I still remember that we are the Usopp pirates!
Good point.
Sounds like it all boils down to whether we were asleep or not.
I'm just pointing out the obvious factors.
It could be a coincidence.
I've never heard of such a case.
I don't know what to think.
Well, now that I've told you what happened, let's hear your story.
Why don't you tell us what you think happened to you yesterday?
I'm pretty sure that I went to pick medicinal herbs with Dr. Reen, and then I went back to the castle and went to bed and woke up here.
Well, I'm being ignored.
I blacked out after getting swallowed up by a giant whirlpool, and then I was here.
Same as these guys.
I remember going to sleep in my room after work, but then I woke up here.
And none of you remember anything after that.
That's right!
There was a horn!
I remember hearing someone blow on a horn!
Same here!
Yeah, horn!
I heard the same thing!
Yeah, me too.
And then, a little boy suddenly appeared out of nowhere.
Hang on.
I don't think we lost our memories.
I get the feeling that kids somehow stole them from us.
Well, we don't know that just yet.
But I'm willing to bet that this child is the answer to our situation.
Do you think it's possible we'll lose more memories each time we fall asleep?
Don't scare me like that!
Look, I mean, this was just a dream, right?
That supernatural kind of mumbo-jumbo isn't real!
You don't think it's weird we all had the same dream?
Supernatural or not, it happened.
Look, I don't mean to scare you, but if this keeps happening,
it could eventually reach a point where you're incapable of remembering who you are.
Nope, still scared!
Say, why is it such a big deal if we remember those things or not?
Huh?
You know, sure, it sucks that I don't have all those fun memories anymore,
but it's a pretty good reason for us to start over and go on new fun adventures!
What?
Are you crazy?
There's a serious chance that we could lose all of our memories!
You really want to lose all your thoughts and dreams and everything?
None of that's gonna happen.
Nothing can take away my dreams.
And I know it's the same for you guys, too.
This guy is freakishly optimistic.
Same old captain.
Doesn't even need his memories to know who he is.
Kinda find him inspiring.
Ah!
My food's gone!
Don't mess with another man's food, got it?
I'm sorry.
There's a good chance that he's crazy.
So I'm the stupid one for taking him seriously.
Alright, where the hell's the town?
This is kind of exciting!
What's that you're making there?
It's a medicine for regaining memories.
No!
Don't interfere!
Find anything useful?
No.
Nothing suggests that it's anything but a normal island.
Alright!
Finally done!
This is my greatest invention yet.
Then I'm sure it's amazing.
Yep.
You called it, my friend.
Behold!
Thanks to me, it doesn't even matter if we lose our memories.
I call them identity boards!
Great idea.
A question mark.
That's just rude.
I am not an emergency food source.
What's with the hearts on mine?
Yep.
Now we'll always know who we are.
Cool, huh?
Don't waste your time on stupid stuff.
So, I'm missing some memories, huh?
It may appear otherwise to the blind eye, but people are quite fragile things.
Zorro.
You're lucky, Zorro.
Being born as a man.
All I ever wanted was to be the world's greatest swordsman.
When girls grow up, it's natural for us to develop into physically weaker beings than men.
It's just so frustrating.
If only, if I'd just been born a man.
Don't go whining like that after you beat me!
Because it's not fair!
You're my goal!
Zorro.
Boy this, girl that, or you're gonna keep up that same kind of talk after I beat you someday!
Like skill is irrelevant!
That's an insult to all of the training I've been pouring on every day!
It's crap!
Now promise me!
Promise me that someday one of us will be the world's greatest swordsman!
We'll compete and see who gets there!
Dummy, you're so weak.
It's a promise!
Sensei, I ask that you let me have that sword.
Her sword?
Kawina's?
That's right!
I'm gonna get stronger than she ever was!
Strong enough that my name reaches up to heaven!
I am going to be the world's greatest swordsman!
I promised her!
I promised!
I did!
Yes.
The sword is yours.
I leave her spirit and her dreams in your hands.
I trained every day after that until I set out to sea in search of that man.
And that's the last I remember.
Falling asleep shortly after getting on a boat.
And after that, it's like nothing else ever happened.
And the weirdest thing about it is these swords.
I have no idea how I got these two.
But they feel so familiar somehow.
None of this makes sense.
Hey, who's back there?
The last date recorded in the logbook is the day before the date on the newspaper.
Which means it's current.
But...
How am I supposed to believe this?
Everything she said.
If it's true...
That would make me a pirate.
Me!
I can't be!
There's no way that it's true.
But then...
This tattoo...
What happened to it?
I don't know what's going on.
I'm so confused.
Greetings and salutations, you pathetic little humans!
From this moment on, this entire island and its inhabitants are a part of my domain!
Starting today, every one of you will pay me for your lives.
Those who cannot pay will die!
No.
I don't want to...
Why do we have to leave?
I...
I want to stay in this village!
It's because we're poor and that's why we can't stay together!
Hold it!
Hmm?
That money I gave up was for my two daughters.
But I can't pay you.
Bidimi!
You can't!
No, it'll be okay.
Really.
I have to do this for my family.
Even if it costs me my life.
It's true the three of us aren't related by blood.
But we're family.
All I've ever wanted was to be their mother.
And now...
Now I can be.
I wish I could have been a better mother to the both of you girls.
Don't say that!
We don't need anything, just don't die!
Nami.
Go and make your dreams come true.
For me.
Hmph.
So.
You ready to die, human?
Nochiko!
Nami!
Love you.
I'm joining the Arlong Pirates.
I'll get to be a navigator and draw maps.
Nami.
I made a deal with Arlong to buy Kokoyashi Village from it.
Buy Kokoyashi?
How?
For a hundred million berries.
But a hundred million berries?
You can't earn that working your whole life!
I will get that money no matter what!
If anyone tries to help me, they'll just get hurt.
Good things will come your way, as long as you continue to live.
I'll be okay.
I'll just smile every time I see his face.
I'm not going to cry anymore.
I'm going to fight by myself.
I miss her so much.
This waiting is killing me.
I'll steal every memory they have left.
Each and every one.
Oh, man.
I'm sorry.
Did I wake you?
No.
Go on back to sleep if you want.
I'll wake you up if I notice anything strange.
I'm okay.
But thanks for keeping a lookout.
How about I brew some coffee to help keep us up?
That sounds great.
I could sure use some.
Well, he didn't waste any damn time, did he?
And right after he swore he wouldn't fall asleep.
What are you two doing up?
Everyone here is supposed to be asleep.
So you're the thief who stole everyone's memories.
I'm surprised you realized.
Not that you can do anything about it.
Come on.
Wake up.
Ah, you've got mystical abilities.
Eh.
What?
Ah!
He's back!
Is it already breakfast time?
That wasn't very nice.
You should have just let them sleep.
I really didn't want to have to do this.
But you've given me no other choice.
Ah!
What do you think you're doing up there?
Huh?
Who said you could sit there?
It's mine!
I cleaned it earlier today!
Don't you dare sit there!
Huh?
Sorry I took your seat.
What the heck is this stuff?
What's happening to him?
I'm scared.
What?
What was that?
Hey, shouldn't we do something for him?
He's not moving.
He's still alive, isn't he?
Doctor!
All right, that's me.
Huh?
He...
I got all my memories back!
I can't.
We'll see you next time.
On the next, Wood Piece.
Now let's get back our memories.
The pirate crew lands on the island.
I'm gonna cut you jerks down.